Hey boys, welcome to the most woke
YouTube channel that's related to Forex,
more specifically, cuz there's
many more woke people than me, including
Alex Becker, true inspiration of this
channel, but he's not as good of a
trader, but he is a little bit more woke
than I am. Anyways, this video is going
to be about how to improve your trading
strategy. Now, whether or not you
already have become profitable, these
statements will still apply and you will
be able to add them into your trading
routine in order to increase your win
rate, increase your profitability,
increase the amount you win each time,
or decrease your losers, something along
those lines. I'm sure you will be able
to follow along. It's quite simple.
Let's jump into it.
Now then, I'm going to be looking at
this in a very analytical way, not
necessarily it's just telling you to
find new strategies, better methods,
things that work better, better trusting
different people. There's going to be a
way that you can analyze it for
yourself,
and then you can figure out for yourself
a method that you already have. This is
an example of something you already
have, you just want to make it a little
bit better each and every time you
trade, each and every month you want to
get a little bit better. Now, this will
take a lot of time. Now, the first thing
that you do need to do is
back test everything. So, anytime you
did get a new strategy that you do want
to test out, see if it's profitable at
all,
you do want to back test that strategy
and make sure that it actually is
profitable or close to profitable so
that you can make those slight
adjustments, things like this. And I
have actually made quite a few videos on
how to back test, there's a video how to
back test like a pro, and there is also
a beginner guide, and this video is
actually within that beginner guide. So,
you guys can look at that back testing
information for yourself, figure out how
you can do that for yourself.
But, check out back testing like a pro,
that's actually how I've back tested in
the past. Now then, once you have a
strategy that you are working with,
let's say it's close to profitable or
it's slightly profitable, something like
this, you want to make it even more
profitable. What you need to do is start
collecting data properly. Now, the
program I suggest is EdgeWonk, and there
should be a link in the description for
the journal that I use. It's a single
time purchase, so it's not like a
recurring monthly thing. It was pretty
cheap, like 200 bucks, something like
this.
So, it wasn't too bad, and it actually
helped me crazily, crazy, crazy.
And what it allows you to do is
basically test different variables,
different styles of trading, different
variations on the same trade. So, every
single time you go into a trade, you can
say, "Okay, what if I took this entry?
What if I took that entry instead?" And
then you can see the differences between
the two lining up beside each other in
the long term across a data set. The
other thing it allows you to majorly do
is test different strategies, tells you
the different win rates, tells you
things like if you do
go into only a slight drawdown on
certain strategies, then maybe you could
tighten up your stop, different things
like this. A lot of great information so
that you can then look at that data and
figure out where you're going to be
slacking. And a very common thing that I
was able to come across when I was using
EdgeWonk or, you know, a similar
software of your choosing,
was some variables weren't profitable or
they were less profitable, something
like this. So, a very, very simple
example is it will tell you that maybe
NZD pairs don't make you money under
this certain strategy, or maybe you're
trading at this time of day and it
doesn't make you money. So, the Asia
session, it doesn't make you money, but
in New York open, it could be making you
money.
So, this is very simple. These are the
very obvious things that are going to
allow you to cut those out and then
increase your win rate or your
profitability per trade, and then you
can be then more profitable in the long
run. This is just something that you do
have to do if you do want to get a
better trading result. You can't just go
willy-nilly going based off feel because
we can know one thing for sure, you
can't trust your emotions. That's why we
think with our brains and not with our
hearts. Hearts are for love, brains are
for trading. Let's keep them separate.
Do not try to combine the two. I know
way too well, and you guys don't have to
do the same as me.
Now, there's tons of other things in
that journaling software, but these are
the major things that were really
standing out as key things that you need
to at least create in your own
journaling software or use that one, and
it's really, really revolving around
having different variables of what you
should be trading, and you should just
do it for everything you can think of.
Think of things like
what was the trade style? Was I trading
the trend? Was there a major spike in
the market? Was there manipulation
before entering the trend? Was there a
momentum shift? What were the candles
looking like? Anything you can think of.
Just start applying all of these
different variables and get as much data
as possible because then you can pick
and choose, and really the data that you
come up with could mean anything to you.
You could come up with something very,
very silly, like, you know, um
just the candle shape right before the
entry, or maybe the daily candle on the
entry or something is bullish or
bearish, something like this. Anything
that you can possibly think of that
might help um
possibly make your strategy a little bit
better. Now, the one last thing that I
would recommend that is super, super
important is you need to reflect weekly
on your trades. At the end of every
single week, you need to have a list of
all of your trades with screenshots, and
you want to go back and you want to
reflect and say, "Hey, what did I do
wrong here?" Look at it from a
non-biased perspective, and then you can
really understand what you were doing
wrong in that particular trade. Make a
note of it. Say in the next week, "Okay,
this is what I'm not going to do." And
then each and every week, that's slowly
going to build on your subconscious, and
you won't make these same kind of silly
mistakes that I know you guys do it.
You're doing it over and over. You kind
of make the same silly mistakes, and
when you do start writing things down,
and you do particularly notice the
things that you are making mistakes week
after week, then you will actually
eventually stop making them. For
example,
you could be jumping into trades too
early, and you would notice that very
quickly with a screenshot. If you always
jump into the trade a little too early,
and then there's a little stop hunt,
gets you out, and then it goes in the
right direction. That will tell you
eventually over time, you know that you
need to be ignoring the jumping into
early, wait a little bit longer, look
for this extra confirmations, things
like this. That might be a great advice
for you guys. Don't jump into anything
too, too early.
Last little quick little point is it's
kind of hard to help you guys with, but
you really need to get your mindset kind
of right, and that's really going to
improve your trading. If you're always
looking at market like you're going to
be losing,
or you're not putting in 100% effort,
you're kind of just going and looking
for the best trade of that day, and
you're not being incredibly, incredibly
strict with your strategy, and you're
not making sure that you're following
all your rules, you're kind of being
lazy, you're not looking at the charts
at the right time, you're not following
that very disciplined rule, you're not
following your diet even. You have to be
a very disciplined person to be able to
be trading, and if your mindset's really
not there, something else on your mind
or you're lazy, then your trading will
also suffer in the exact same manner.
So, if you change one thing in your
life, start reading a book every single
day, that will actually in turn help
your trading just because you are
improving your discipline. That's
absolutely everything for me, guys. I
hope that I was helpful. If you do like
this video, please make sure you hit the
like button, hit the subscribe button if
you're new to the channel so you can
join in on the streams and learn some
actual really reading real, real
trading. And if you guys are interested,
you can follow me on Instagram for a
couple little signals here and there,
photos, and follow along the lifestyle.
See you guys next time.
Listen.
Oh, I I